-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
愿你坠入地狱 炼狱之火燃烧不歇
Jezerael burn forever and a day.
愿你邪恶的身躯为豺狼所吞噬
May thy foul prophecy food for the jackals
你的血因此而变得纯洁
and thy blood crave for purity.
最后的吸血鬼
The Last Vampyre
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
我觉得我说服了她
I thought I persuaded her.
我们将请您在这个教堂里为孩子洗礼
We'd have the baby baptized here in this church by you.
你明白女人
Well you know women.
邻村有一个天主教堂
Oh there's a Catholic church in the next village.
Carlotta发现了它
Carlotta has found it.
星期天我们将分头行事
On Sunday's we go our separate ways.
那小孩呢?
And the child?
不 不 不
No, No, No,
他跟我在一起
He stays with me.
这点我很坚持
I'm resolved on that.
其他事情你太太都适应了吧?
Most other things your wife has adapted well?
噢 是的
Oh indeed.
我们的气候呢?
Our climate?
不 气候不行
No not the climate.
你的孩子 Jack 他的反应如何?
Your boy, Jack, how is he responding?
呃 这个我们也会很快解决的
Well we'll resolve that too in good time.
对你来说可不容易
Not easy for you.
是的 不过我爱我的妻子
No but I love my wife about this
而爱能征服一切
and love conquers all
这可是您布道的时候常说的
as you've always preached from your pulpit.
噢 Stockton 今晚晚餐在八点钟
Oh Stockton? Dinner tonight eight o'clock.
八点钟
Eight o'clock.
有意思的一个人
Interesting man.
你说对了 他是在秘鲁呆过一段时间
And you were right he has spent some time in Peru.
我已经邀请他过来了
I've invited him over
这样可以让Carlotta有回家的感觉
to make Carlotta feel at home.
从这儿滚开!
Go away from here!
杀人犯!
Murderer!
你不要再吵了
You stop this noise.
现在 求你了
Now please.
你惊扰到小孩了
You upset baby.
你没听到吗?
Don't you hear?
你要是让我吻你的话 我会停下来的
I'll stop if you let me kiss you.
吻吗?
Kiss?
你要吻我吗 Jack?
You kiss me Jack?
吻哪儿?
Where?
你想吻哪儿?
Where you wish?
双唇吗?
On the lips?
还是脖子?
On the neck?
靴子
On the boot.
你吻我的靴子
You kiss my boot.
来啊 如果你那么渴望
come on if you want it so bad.
谢谢 Michael
Thank you Michael.
今晚我们请了一位客人来用晚餐
We've got a guest coming for dinner tonight.
好的 先生
Yes sir.
Stockton先生
Mr. Stockton.
我让他别拉了 而他竟然侮辱我 太太
I tell him to stop and he insult me senora.
Jack 立刻停下来
Jack stop at once.
停下!
Stop!
把它给我
Give it to me.
他吓到小孩了
He frightened the baby.
我什么也没干 父亲
I did nothing Father.
我在院子里就听见你拉琴了 孩子
I heard you from the yard boy.
你干嘛要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
为什么?
Why?
我一直想要的就是你
You are all I've ever desired.
我会冻死的
I shall die of cold.
不 不会的
No you won't.
一个愉快的夜晚会让你很快暖和起来
A convivial evening will soon warm your bones.
之前发生的事情我很抱歉
I'm sorry what happened earlier
但是那孩子对Delores很粗鲁 非常粗鲁
but the boy was rude to the Delores, very rude.
你应该让我来教育他
You must leave him to me.
即使如此...用这个给他买把新的提琴
Even so this is for a new violin.
没什么的 为什么不呢?
Of course why not?
Jack?
我的孩子 你继母...
My boy your stepmother's...
我们的客人已经到了 父亲
Our guest has arrived father.
Stockton 亲爱的朋友
Stockton my dear fellow.
我的妻子 Carlotta
My wife Carlotta.
很高兴认识你
Mucho gusto.
这是我的孩子 Jack
My boy Jack.
就是那位小提琴家?
The violinist?
你们见过面?
You met each other?
在村子里见过 父亲
In the village father.
我们谈到了远足
We talked about hiking.
晚饭后为我们演奏吧?
You'll play for us after dinner?
我拉得还不够好
I'm not good enough.
这是我们的骄傲和欢乐 我的儿子Ricardo
And our pride and joy my son Ricardo.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
你还好吧 老伙计?
You alright old man?
抱歉吓到你了 华生
Sorry to have alarmed you Watson
但是你的反应是很有启发性的
but your reaction was instructive.
那么你相信它们是存在的了?
So you believe in their existence?
什么?
What?
吸血鬼
Vampires.
不 我当然不信
No of course I don't.
可你的反应正好相反
You're attitude suggests the contrary.
一个人被某种东西吓倒 并不意味着就相信它的存在
No one has to believe in something to be frightened of.
这个分属于大脑的两个不同区域
It's two different parts of the brain.
没错
Right.
那么你就把它们排除了
So you rule them out
吸血鬼 哼
Vampires.
你的理性让你坚持这种看法
The rational part of you insists upon it.
那你相信它们的存在喽?
Well do you believe in them?
看一眼这个
Cast your eyes over this.
老Drury街46号   四月十二日
46 Old Drury April 12th.
回复: 吸血鬼
Re: Vampires.
鄙公司委托人
Our client, The Revered Locastos Merridew
来自Lamberley教区 尊敬的Locastos Merridew牧师
of the Vicar's Lamberley
在今天的事务中
has made some inquiry from us
向我们咨询
in a communication of even date
有关...有关吸血鬼的事情
concerning...concerning vampires.
由于鄙公司专营
As our firm specializes entirely
机械估价业务
upon the assessment of machinery,
此事完全 不在我们的业务范围之内
the matter hardly comes within our purview.
噢!
Oh!
噢 亲爱的Ruddock小姐
Oh my dear Miss Ruddock.
可怜啊 我是个可怜的女人
Wretched wretched woman I am.
什么事让你心神不宁?
What disturbed you?
我们因此介绍Merridew牧师
We Have therefore recommended the Reverend Merridew
来造访您并陈述详情
to call on you and lay the matter before you.
阁下成功破解Matilda Briggs一案
We have not forgotten your successful action
所予鄙公司之帮助永志难忘
in the case of Matilda Briggs.
您忠诚的
We are sirs, faithfully yours,
Morrison Morrison&Dodd公司
Morrison, Morrison and Dodd.
这副杯碟在这儿 已有三天了
This cup and saucer has been here for the last 3 days.
Matilda Briggs是一艘船
Matilda Briggs' was a ship
与苏门答腊岛的大老鼠有关
associated with the giant rat of Sumatra
一个世人还没有做好心理准备的故事
a story for which the world is not yet prepared.
就算如此 你觉得
You consider though that
吸血鬼就是我们的业务范围?
vampires should come within our purview?
不是
No.
什么事都比目前这种没事干好啊
Anything is better than this stagnation.
真的
Really?
我们似乎转向
We seemed to have been switched on
某种格林童话之类的案子了
to some Grimm's fairytale.
呃 这个Merridew可是个神职人员
Well this Merridew is a man of the cloth.
一个信仰基督教的人
A man of Christian belief.
那正是勉强算得上有趣的一点了
That is of marginal interest.
把手伸长了 华生
Make a long arm, Watson,
让我们查查字母V 看有什么说法
Iet us see what the 'V' has to say.
Gloria Scott航行记
Voyage of the Gloria Scott
那是个很糟的案件
that was a bad business.
我还记得
I have some recollection
你还做了些记录 华生
that you made a record of it Watson,
虽然结果并不值得祝贺
though I was unable to congratulate you upon the result.
造伪钞者Victor Lynch
Victor Lynch and the forger,
有毒的蜥蜴或叫大毒蜥
the Venomous Lizard or Gila,
那是个很不寻常的案子
remarkable case that.
马戏团美女Victoria
Victoria, the circus belle.
强盗Vanderbilt
Vanderbilt and the Yeggman.
我想喝点茶 福尔摩斯
I should like some tea Holmes.
毒贩
Vipers.
奇异锻工Vigor...
Vigor and the Hammersmith Wonder...
你说什么?
did you say something?
要不要我叫人送些茶上来?
Shall I call down for some tea?
很好的旧索引
Good old index.
你知道你难不倒它
You know you can't beat it.
听听这个:匈牙利的吸血鬼
Listen to this, vampirism in Hungary
还有Transylvania的吸血鬼
and again vampires in Transylvania.
亲爱的朋友 发生什么事了?
My dear friend what has happened?
您能马上来一趟吗?
Will you come at once?
是的 当然可以
Yes of course.
垃圾 华生 都是些垃圾
Rubbish Watson rubbish.
这些得在它们心脏里插上木棍
What are we to do with walking corpses
才能让它们呆在坟墓里的行尸
that have to have stakes driven through their hearts
跟我们有什么关系?
to keep them in their graves?
这样的东西真值得我们关注吗?
Are we to give serious attention to such things?
完全是精神失常
It's pure lunacy.
呃 毫无疑问你是对的
Well no doubt your right.
我们这个事务所
This agency
应该坚守它自己的立场
must stand flat footed upon the ground of that it is to remain.
世界对我们来说够大了
The world is big enough for us.
没必要再去管什么鬼的事情
No ghost need apply.
噢 对哦 鬼嘛...
Awe well now ghosts...
却要我们去管
Need apply.
你打不打算告诉我
Are you prepared to tell me
这些是谁给你的?
who supplied you with these?
还有给你干嘛?
And to what purpose?
呃 我让Pachum的一个牙医
Well I had them made for me
给我做的
by a dentist from Pachum.
是我曾经一次需要的必要伪装
It was a necessary disguise I needed once.
我忘了
I forget.
那你用过它们吗?
And did you put them to use?
颇具打击性的幽默哦 华生
Balking humor again Watson.
你真的要克制这种做法
You really must guard against it.
Albert?
街上有个人给了我这个 先生
A man gave me this in the street sir.
一位上了年纪的先生
Elderly gent,
他说他有急事要见您
he says he's got to see you urgent.
就是你那位牧师
It's your man of the cloth.
让他进来吧
Show him up.
小心些
With care.
好的 先生
Yes sir.
噢 Albert?
Oh Albert?
先生?
Sir?
你相信世上有吸血鬼吗?
Do you believe in the existence of vampires?
噢 是的 非常相信 先生
Oh yeah, most definitely sir.
这是智慧的声音
There speaks the voice of wisdom.
我相信并无实在经历
No experience I trust.
好啦 谢谢你 年轻人
Yes thank you young man.
我还不算老朽
I'm not quite in my grave yet.
你好 福尔摩斯先生
Hello Mr. Holmes,
这么急来找你 你能见我真好
this is so good of you to see me on such notice.
我知道你有多忙
I know how busy you are.
请坐下 牧师
Sit down and settle yourself Reverend.
谢谢
Thank you.
麻烦你叫Wiggins送些茶进来好吗?
Will you tell Wiggins to bring in the tea?
-好的 先生 -谢谢 Albert
-Yes sir. -Thank you Albert.
这位是我的朋友和同事
This is my friend and colleague.
华生医生 是的...是的 我认识
Doctor Watson yes...yes I know.
我的顾问
Now my solicitors,
Morrison 来自Morrison&...
Morrison, Morrison and...
Dodd公司?
Dodd?
事实上他们并非真是我的顾问
Point of fact there not really my solicitors
不是的 很久前我跟他们有些往来
no I had some dealings with them long ago.
我不太记得是关于什么事的了
I forget quite what about.
机械
Machinery.
是吗?
Was it?
呃 不管怎么说
Well anyway
我是代表我的朋友和我本人到这儿来的
I'm here on behalf of a friend of mine and myself too.
我非常希望你们不要
And I'm very anxious you shouldn't take me
把我当成一个老傻瓜
for a complete old fool.
不会的
Please.
你慢慢说
You must take your time.
从何说起呢
Where to start it all.
我是Lamberley教区的牧师
I'm Vicar of Lamberley;
我在那地方呆了很久了
I've been there longer than I care to think.
是该走人的时候了
Only time to go but
不过让我跟你谈谈Bob Ferguson
Iet me tell you about Bob Ferguson.
不会是Richmond的Bob Ferguson吧?
Not Bob Ferguson of Richmond?
他也记得你 医生
He remembers you too Doctor
你们在橄榄球场上结识
from the rugby field.
他也许是最好的三分卫
Possibly the finest three-quarter
不过不曾为英格兰出赛过
never to have been capped for England.
我就是这样看的
And my sentiments precisely.
我热爱这项运动
I love the game and
毫不谦虚地说 我曾经打得不错
if modesty permits I once turned out myself quite a player.
Bob在国外工作了很多年
Well Bob has spent much most of his working life abroad.
做棉花贸易
Cotton brooking.
他跟他前妻生了一个孩子叫Jack
Now his first wife, by whom he has a son Jack,
几年前他妻子死于高烧...
she died of fever some years ago and...
瞧 我觉得很有必要让你
Iook it's absolutely essential
了解事情的全貌
that I put you in the full picture.
就这样接着讲下去吧 牧师
Continue just as you're doing Reverend.
福尔摩斯经常是
It is often Holmes' method
紧闭着双眼
to absorb all
把所有的细节都听进去
relevant detail with his eyes tight shut.
Bob最近回到了家乡
Well Bob arrived home recently
带了一位从秘鲁来的新娘 和他们襁褓中的孩子
with a new bride and a baby from Peru.
对于所有有关的人来说 都是一场艰难的改变
Difficult transition for all concerned
这个你想象得到
as you may imagine.
你会骑马吗 Jack?
You ride Jack?
-不会 -他当然会了
-No. -Of course he rides.
还是我教的呢
I taught him.
所有的事情都是我教给你的 对吧Jack?
Taught you everything didn't I Jack?
不过我得让你注意一位陌生人
But I must turn your attention to a stranger
就在这一家从秘鲁回来前 他先来到了我们这里
who came into our midst not long before our Peruvian family.
他叫John Stockton
His name is John Stockton.
呃 起初我很欢迎他
Well at first I welcomed him
把他当作是一个知识分子 一个作家
as a man of intellect,a writer
一个能给我们小小的社区带来生机的人
and stimulus to our little community.
噢 谢谢
Oh thank you.
不能说我个人对他有什么好感
I can't say that I warmed to him personally
不过对于我这样一个
but he did have his own appeal
窝在穷乡僻壤的人
to someone like myself,
他的确有着吸引力
buried in the backwater.
他对我虽然不具什么威胁 却让当地人颇为不安
He was not threat to me but he upset the locals.
我们的铁匠Carter
our blacksmith, Carter.
和他就一个车轮起了争执
Some argument over a wheel.
你以为你是谁 敢跑来告诉我该怎么做? 你这该死的!
Who are you come telling me my job damn you?
你要是不喜欢它 就把它带走
If you don't like it you can take it away.
另请高明!
Find somebody else!
你跟它一起滚 别再回来了!
And take yourself with it and don't come back.
我们这个村子不欢迎你!
We don't want you here in this village.
这里没人欢迎你!
None of us!
Carter正值壮年 彪悍得像头狮子
Carter, a lion of a man in the prime of life
乡村生活造就了他强壮的体格
Stalwart of village life,
结果当下就死了
dead within moments of it.
我教区有一个老小姐叫Ruddock
Now Miss Ruddock, spinster of my parish,
她的农舍正对着Stockton的屋子
she has the cottage facing Stockton's.
她说他是一个不用睡觉的人
And she speaks of him as the man who never sleeps.
她很多个晚上都看到 他屋里彻夜点着蜡烛直到天亮
She sees a candle in his window many a nights through till dawn.
呃 作家在晚上写作 也不算稀奇
Well writers work it's not uncommon.
有可能
Possibly
不过我自己因为失眠
but I myself am something of an insomniac also
也曾有两次 深夜在墓地里见过他
I have seen him twice in my graveyard at dead of night.
他是怎么解释的?
And his explanation?
啊?
Huh?
你肯定提起过这件事吧?
Surely you raised the matter?
解释吗?
Explanation?
看似可信吧 我想
Plausible I suppose.
我想我跟一家叫Sinclair的有些亲戚关系
I believe that I'm related to a family called Sinclair,
它正是我的中间名
indeed my middle name.
Sinclair?
他们在村子的那一头有一栋大房子
They had a large house up beyond the village.
是的 你这么说我想起来了
Yes now you mention it.
我很奇怪在这里找不到任何他们的踪迹
I'm puzzled to find no trace of them.
难道我们在这里不受欢迎吗?
Are we not welcome here?
其实不是的
No the truth was
事实是我很清楚Sinclair一家的故事
that I knew full well the story of the Sinclair's.
他们是很有权势的地主
They were powerful landowners,
整个村子都是他们的
had the village in their pocket
大概是上个世纪的事情了
sometime in the last century.
Sinclair本人是个残忍的怪物
The Lord Sinclair himself was a cruel monster.
那些招惹他的人不是失踪了
Those who incurred his displeasure disappeared
就是被人割断了喉咙
or were found with their throats cut.
年轻的女仆中有一个
Young servant girls, one in particular,
怀着孩子被遗弃在教堂门口 奄奄一息
was left pregnant and dying at the church door,
她的孩子生下来就死了
her child stillborn.
一个姓Sinclair的都找不到
There's not a Sinclair to be found.
我们做了什么让人如此憎恨的事情?
What did we do to offend?
你有没有告诉他?
Did you tell him?
呃 说了个大概
Well the bare bones of it yes.
那起教堂事件
The church incident
还有村民们如何实施了
and how the villagers exacted
可怕的复仇
their terrible revenge.
把我们的人都烧死了?
Burnt us out?
很抱歉这么说
I regret to say,
当然不是针对你本人的
nothing personal to you of course.
那个女孩呢?
And the girl?
就埋在那边
She's buried over there.
但是我没有告诉他一件事情
But what I neglected to tell him
因为说了不太合适
because it seemed to be inappropriate
那就是Sinclair家
was that the family Sinclair
被认为是吸血鬼
were deemed to be vampires.
你说的事情都很有意思 牧师
All of this is very interesting Reverend.
不过这都是过去的事了
as piece of history
跟现在又怎么扯上关系了?
but how does it lead to the present?
呃 Sinclair自己都承认了
Well then Sinclair by his own admission
他回来了 不是吗?
has returned hasn't he?
可对村子又有什么影响呢?
But how does that affect the village?
村里人干嘛要在乎呢?
And why should they care?
所有的这些都发生在一百年前啊
All of this happened a hundred years back.
是的 不过你知道的...有些传言...
Yes well...word gets around you know?
你是说教堂吗?
You mean the church?
深受流言的影响
Profound to all gossip.
回答你的第二个问题吧
Answering your second question
那个女孩 那个死去的女孩
the girl, the dead girl,
她的后人还生活在这个村子里
her family is still in the village.
比如当地旅馆的老板娘
The wife of the landlord of the local inn for instance
她就是姓Barrows的
she was a Barrows.
还有铁匠的妻子
So too was the blacksmith's wife.
据你所知
Has Stockton, to your knowledge,
Stockton是否进过教堂?
ever set foot inside the church?
噢 一次也没有  据我所知 从来都没有
Oh no not once as far as I'm aware of it...never.
既便如此
Even so,
我还是不清楚我能帮你什么忙
I'm unclear that I can be of service to you.
又没有犯下什么罪行
No crime has been committed.
没有罪行?
No crime?
是的...没有任何犯罪? 但是...
No...no crime? But...
你还有什么要告诉我们的吗?
You have something more to tell us?
四天前...现在看来像是过了一辈子
4 days ago now, it seems a lifetime;
Bob Ferguson邀请Stockton去吃饭
Bob Ferguson invited Stockton to dinner.
你知道Stockton在秘鲁旅行过
You see, Stockton had traveled in Peru
我想是我对他提过
and I think it was I who suggested
说让他的新太太重新
that it might be a good thing for his new wife
跟自己的故乡建立些联系是件好事
to have some contact again with her native country.
难道那并非是个
And the evening
成功的夜晚?
not a success?
我所知道的就是
All I know is
那个晚上结果演变成一场悲剧
that the outcome of it was a tragedy.
就在第二天早上
The very next morning
那家人醒来发现了一件可怕的事情
the household woke to a terrible discovery.
那个婴孩 Ricardo 死在他的小床上
The baby, little Ricardo, lay dead in his cot.
医生的结论呢?
And the doctor's verdict.
医生找不到任何致死的原因
The doctor he could find no reason for it.
没有可能的原因
No earthly reason.
真是一场悲剧
Tragedy indeed.
但是晚宴的客人的确没有什么好指责的吧?
But no blame affixed to the dinner guest surely?
可是他碰了婴孩的手
But he touched the baby's hand.
他们就是这么告诉我的
So they told me.
瞧 我是个牧师 先生们
Look I'm a man of God gentlemen
我绝对不会
and far be it for me
单凭谣言或是迷信
to judge a fellow being
就对一个人下结论
on hearsay and superstition
可是我也要考虑我的教民们
but I also have my parishioners to think of
他们都吓得要命
and their frightened
他们将会采取非法律途径
and they will take steps outside the law
来把他赶出去
to drive him out
就像以前对待他的祖先那样
as they once did his forbearers.
你明白我的两难境地了吧?
You see my dilemma?
那么你希望我们进行调查?
So you wish us to make an investigation
调查这个人以及他的为人和生活习惯?
into this man, his personality, his habits?
以证实大众的担心是毫无理由的?
And disprove the common fear?
证明或是驳斥 随便你们
Disprove, disprove what you will.
只要你一出现
You're presence alone
就能起到安定民心的效果
will have a steadying affect.
我现在得走了
Well now I must leave you.
我还得操心的是
Among my other concerns
村里的疾病
is sickness in the village
而且我还得为明天婴儿的葬礼
and I have the baby's funeral
做好准备
to prepare for tomorrow.
你的故事真复杂 牧师
Your story is complex Reverend.
不过却是很有意思
But none of that's uninterest.
我相信应该有合理的解释
Yet I'm sure there's a rational explanation for it.
华生和我将会到您的教区去
Watson and I will visit your community.
噢 我太高兴了
Oh I'm so pleased.
您提到了一个旅馆
You mentioned an inn.
是的 叫Checquers 是个像样的地方
Yes the Checquers, it's a decently run place.
呃 谢谢
Well thank you.
我非常地感激
I'm so grateful.
感激你们二位
So grateful to you both.
非常感激
So grateful.
好的 两起突然的死亡事件
All right, 2 sudden deaths,
铁匠和婴儿
the blacksmith and the child,
就在和他接触后不久
shortly after contact.
自然死亡
Natural causes,
验尸官的报告会这么说
as the coroner's report will inform us.
Stockton夜里的习惯
Stockton's nocturnal habits
还有窗后的烛光?
the light in the window?
写作不顺罢了
Writer's block.
他对天黑以后的墓地怀有的病态兴趣?
His morbid interest in graveyards after dark?
对"病态"这个词我不敢苟同
I object the word morbid.
这是一种动机但并非事实
It's a motive not fact.
好吧 那从不进教堂又怎么说?
All right, never entering the church?
这可是你自己提出来的
You raised that point yourself.
是似乎从未进过教堂
Never seemed to enter the church
是不是因为他没有宗教信仰
and does that make a man a ghoul
就可以断定他为盗尸贼?
because he has no interest in religion?
那在Ferguson房子里做客的夜晚呢?
The evening spent in Ferguson's house?
牧师是否在现场?
Was the Vicar there?
没有 不过Merridew告诉过我们
No but Merridew tells us
Stockton碰了那婴孩的手
that Stockton touched the baby's hand.
那是你的案子吗?
Is that your case?
那我们到这儿干嘛来了?
So what is our mission here?
也许是来阻止一次犯罪
Possibly to prevent a crime.
这个人的心脏就要被插上木棍了
A man having a stake driven through his heart.
我们的时机正合适
We have our timing right.
福尔摩斯 我们不能强行闯进去
Holmes we can scarcely intrude.
不是闯进去 华生 是观察
Not intrude Watson, observe.
我想知道Stockton是不是在这里
I wonder if Stockton's here
这种场合他不可能会露面的
He's hardly likely to show is face on this occasion.
他是最近晚宴的客人 还是这家人的朋友
A recent dinner guest, a friend of the family.
在这种情形下 不会的
In the circumstances no.
我想你是对的
Yes I'm sure you're right.
但是我知道他就在不远处
But I know he's not far away.
一位女士的儿子
Man that is born of woman
只活了短短的一生
hath but a short time to live
充满了痛苦
and is full of misery.
他像彗星般掠过 又如花朵般夭折
He cometh up and is cut down like a flower.
他像个影子般匆匆而过
He fleeth as it were a shadow.
就再也没有留下
A never continueth in one's stay.
在生命的旅途中 我们陷入死亡
In the midst of life we are in death.
除了您 我们还可以向谁求助呢 我们的主啊
Of whom may we seek for succor but of thee O' Lord
您应该为我们的罪过而恼怒
who for our sins are justly displeased
我们谦恭地恳求您 主啊
we meekly beseech the O' Father
把我们从罪的死亡中解救出来
to raise us from the death of sin
升入正义的九天
unto the life of righteousness.
祈求当我们死去
That when we shall depart this life
我们能在他的怀抱里安息
we may rest in him,
希望我们的这位教友亦是如此
as our hope is this our brother does.
在最后审判日的复活中
That the general resurrection in the last day
我们能为您所接受
we may be found acceptable in thy sight
得到您的祝福...
and receive that blessing which thy...
Jack在八九岁的时候从一棵树上摔了下来
Jack fell from a tree when he was eight or nine.
伤了脊椎骨 可怜的Jack
Damaged his spine boy oh Jack.
当时
But father,
那位父亲是在这里还是在国外?
was he here or abroad when it happened?
呃 我想他当时不在这儿
Well I do believe he was away yes.
几乎没有父母亲的童年
A boyhood almost without it's mother or father.
呃 在这儿我是他的精神导师
Well I was here as his spiritual guardian
还有Mason太太
and Mrs. Mason,
农场来的女管家
the housekeeper from the farm,
她把他和她自己的孩子Michael一起养大
she brought him up with her own boy Michael.
这些死亡记录 福尔摩斯 好多人啊
These recorded deaths Holmes so many of them,
都这么年轻
so young.
也许是流感盛行
An influenza epidemic perhaps.
就像现在一样
As we have now upon us.
如果Stockton是一个复仇者的话
If Stockton is perceived as some sort of avenger
他干嘛要选中Ferguson一家?
why should he light upon the Ferguson's?
他们的家族一百年前并不在这里啊
I mean they weren't here a hundred years ago.
即使是现在他们也没有 融入这里的乡村生活
Even now they're scarcely apart of the village life.
为什么呢?
So why?
他们怎么会勾起他的兴趣的?
Why is he drawn to them?
这个女士 还有跟秘鲁的联系?
The women, the connection with Peru?
还是因为就近选择?
Or is it something nearer home?
你跟本地的医生交上朋友了吗?
Did you make friends with the local doctor?
不是什么朋友
Hardly friends
他对我颇为猜疑
as I was greeted with deep suspicion.
我不得不用我30年前
Had to plead my rugby acquaintanceship
跟Ferguson的橄榄球缘作为借口
with Ferguson that goes back 30 years.
他在老Deer公园球场
He threw me over the ropes into the crowd
把我扔过了绳栏 扔到了人群中
at the Old Deer Park.
你怎么解释你的出现?
How do you explain your presence here?
呃 我觉得我们不会在这里呆很久的
Well I cant believe that we'll be detained here long.
另一份验尸报告
Another coroner's report.
铁匠Carter死于出血
Blacksmith, Carter, died of a hemorrhage.
也许他看上去是健壮如牛
He may have look robust but he was overweight
不过他体重超标又喝很多酒
and he drank too much.
那婴儿呢?
And the baby?
记录为肺炎
Put down to pneumonia.
没有暴力的迹象?
No sign of violence?
没有
No.
跟我们想的一样
Just as we thought.
现在去拜访Ferguson如何?
What now a visit to Ferguson?
以示尊敬?
Pay our respects?
不去
No.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
Jack
Jack.
Jack在哪儿?
Where's Jack?
他是在下面跟你在一起吗?
Is he down with you?
没有
No.
从下午到现在 我没有看见过他也没有听到他的声音
I haven't seen sight nor sound of him since this afternoon.
葬礼之后他没有回来过吗?
He didn't come back here after the funeral?
我问问Michael看他是否见到过他
I'll ask Michael if he's seen him.
好的
Yes.
这是给Ferguson太太的吗?
Is that for Mrs. Ferguson?
是的 鸡汤
Yes, chicken broth.
她得吃点东西才行
She must eat something.
我拿上去吧
I'll take it up to her.
谢谢 管家太太
Thank you my lady.
不要吃的
No food.
她睡着了 先生 别吵醒她
She's sleep now sir, no wake her up.
这个我来做主 Dolores
I'll decide that Dolores.
谢谢
Thank you.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
走开!
Go away!
还要我拿点别的吗 先生们?
Anything more I can get you gentlemen?
这个太棒了
This is excellent.
不要了 谢谢
No thank you.
一杯水 谢谢
Glass of water thank you.
他们都看见你了 Michael
You were seen Michael.
他们就是看见你了 不承认也没用
Yes you were and there's no denying it.
整个仪式中都抓着你的胳膊
Clutching your arm right through that service.
不是我干的 Vera
It wasn't my doing Vera.
她很沉痛
She was grieving.
需要一个男人的支撑
She needed the support of a man.
就因为她是外国来的还很漂亮吗?
Just cause she's foreign and beautiful?
不像你一样会骑马
Not ride a horse like you.
噢 骑马又怎么啦?
Oh what's it matter riding horses?
我肯定你亲了她了 我了解你
I bet you kissed her knowing you.
亲她?
Kissed her?
要是那样的话我的下巴都会被打碎的
I'd get my jaw broken with that one.
她脾气暴躁
She's fiery.
你不就喜欢那样的吗
It's just how you like it.
没错
That's right.
就像你一样全身羽毛都竖起来了
All ruffled feathers my dear.
-来吧 我们到外面去 -不要! 走开!
-Come on let's step outside.. -No get off.
-噢 来吧 -不 Michael!
-Oh come one. -No Michael!
我今晚不舒服
I'm not feeling very well tonight.
谢谢
Thank you.
这牛排和腰子布丁
This steak and kidney pudding
果然名副其实
is every bit as good as it's reputation
你不觉得吗 华生?
wouldn't you say Watson?
是的 名副其实
Yes every bit.
你在贝克街可是出了名啊 Gresty太太
You're famous in Beggar Street Mrs. Gresty.
我们的管家 Hudson太太
Our housekeeper Mrs. Hudson
向我们推荐了你
put us onto you.
Hudson太太?
Mrs. Hudson?
她有个妹妹住在这儿附近
She has a sister who lives near by.
噢
Oh.
呃 你要夸就夸我先生
Well it's my husband you have to compliment.
东西主要都是他煮的
It's him who does the cooking mostly.
那么你就是歇洛克 福尔摩斯?
So you are Sherlock Holmes?
听候您差遣
At your service.
你们来这儿办案的吗?
On a case there are ya?
噢 这里肯定...
Oh surely there is no crime
没有什么罪案的啦
in this part of the country.
请我们的男主人喝上一杯 华生
Drinks for our host Watson,
也请大伙儿喝一杯
drinks all around.
当然好了
Yes of course.
噢 华生医生
Oh Doctor Watson
他是Ferguson先生以前的一位橄榄球友
is an old rugby-playing friend of Mr. Ferguson.
对他和他的家人来说这事儿真够惨的
It's a tragedy about him and his family.
你想跟Michael谈谈吗?
You want to talk to Michael about that.
他们发现那可怜的孩子时他就在那儿
He was there when they found the poor mate.
那也不是什么意外死亡
And it wasn't no accidental death neither.
别的什么都有可能
Whatever else it was
唯独不是一起意外
it wasn't no accident.
Jack你去哪儿了?
Jack where've you been?
我很担心
I was worried.
我以为你想跟Carlotta独处一下
I thought you'd want to be alone with Carlotta.
我需要你
I needed you.
此刻我需要我们像一家人那样团结在一起
I needed us together as a family this time.
我们所有人在一起
All of us together.
您是对的 牧师
You are right Reverend.
空气中弥漫着一种危险的气氛
There is a dangerous mood in the air.
但是并没有任何对Stockton不利的证据
But no fresh evidence against Stockton.
这种巧合还是让我无法平静
I'm still struck by the coincidence.
呃 回答我的这个问题 福尔摩斯
Well answer me this Holmes.
要是真没什么的话
Why is so much being written and recorded
为什么还有那么多记载
on the subject of vampires
是关于吸血鬼的?
if there's absolutely nothing in it?
这是人类的需要 华生
Man's need Watson.
出于对恐惧的解释的需要
His need to explain fear.
那么你承认有些事情是无法解释的了?
Then you do admit to the inexplicable?
是的 有非常多的证据表明这点
Well yes there's plenty evidence of that.
但是你是否会因为有很多人写过
But do you believe in dragons
就相信有龙的存在
and fairies and ghosts
还相信仙女和鬼?
because much has been written about them?
鬼?
Ghosts?
华生有个鬼故事要讲
Watson has a ghost story.
不是说这个的时候 老兄
Not now man.
不 说吧  华生
No carry on Watson.
当时我在阿富汗
I was in Afghanistan.
经历了许多疲劳的长夜
Long nights of fatigue.
在一个战地医院里
In a field hospital.
有一个年轻中尉死了
A young subaltern,
事实上他就死在我的怀里
who had died, virtually in my arms,
在他过世的几周后 我在伊斯坦布尔休假
appeared some weeks later quite unmistakably
他分明就出现在了那儿
when I was on leave in Constantinople.
真有意思
Fascinating.
先生们
Gentleman.
歇洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
久仰 福尔摩斯先生
Yes of course Mr. Holmes.
还有华生医生 我想你认识他
And Dr. Watson I believe you know.
华生 亲爱的朋友
Watson, my dear fellow.
请进 请进
Come inside, come inside.
- 亲爱的朋友 谨致以诚挚的哀悼 - 谢谢
My dear chap I sincere condolences... Thank you.
Mason小姐 为客人上咖啡
Coffee for our guest Miss Mason.
都准备好了 先生
It's ready and waiting sir.
我的难得的好管家
My treasured housekeeper.
要是没有她我们都不知道怎么办
We'd be lost without her.
噢 请坐
Oh sit down please.
Augustus向我解释了你们来这儿的原因
Augustus has explained your presence here
我非常认同他的主动帮忙
and heartily endorse his initiative.
这是个悲惨的时刻
This has been wretched time
不只是对我和我的家人
not just for me and my family
对于整个社区而言也一样
but for the whole community.
我们越快弄明白越好
The sooner we make sense of it the better.
你的爱妻呢?
Your dear wife?
是的 我本来很想要她也到场的
Yes I would have liked for her to be here.
她在楼上自己的房间里
She's upstairs in her room.
你见过Stockton了吗?
Have you met Stockton yet?
还未有幸会面 Ferguson先生
We've not had that pleasure Mr. Ferguson.
有幸?
Pleasure?
噢 是的 我第一次认识他的时候
Oh yes he seemed he was pleasant enough
他似乎是个令人愉快的人
on my first acquaintance.
我可以问你问题吗?
May I ask you?
您随便问 福尔摩斯先生
Ask anything Mr. Holmes.
问什么都行
Anything.
在某种程度上我们是不是把你孩子的死
Are we some way holding Stockton responsible
归咎于Stockton了?
for your child's death?
也许在某种程度上我们都要负上些责任
Perhaps were all responsible to some degree.
当然我妻子责怪我
Certainly my wife holds me responsible
把她带到英国来
for bringing her here to England.
小孩还不满一岁 还有气候 欧洲
The child not a year old, the climate, Europe,
也许我盼着能通过归咎于他人
perhaps I'm looking to alleviate responsibility.
来减轻些自己的责任
By directing it at another.
请你原谅我的坦率
Please you must excuse my frankness.
但如果想要弄清问题的实质 我们则很有必要
But it is necessary that we confront the truth about ourselves
面对我们真实的内心
if we are to reach the heart of this matter.
你一点也没错 福尔摩斯先生
Your absolutely right Mr. Holmes.
事实的真相
The truth of the matter.
你能不能跟我们说说
Could you bring yourself to tell us about
Stockton来用餐的那个晚上?
the evening Stockton came over to dinner?
我想那晚你开始
Which I understand
对他充满疑虑
was the start of your misgivings about him.
好的
Yes.
那天晚上... 那时我自己也不是很明白
That night I didn't see it clearly myself at the time.
晚餐平安无事
Dinner had passed uneventfully
虽然我得承认
though I confess
我对我的客人有些失望
I was somewhat disappointed by our guest.
他的行为
His demeanor.
灵魂的本性...
The real nature of the soul.
到底是什么呢
Well what is it
对于某些人而言它只不过是意愿的体现
to some merely a manifestation of the will.
但是灵魂会回归造物主
But the soul returns to God.
就像一个声音在空气中消失无踪
Like a sound that vanishes in the air.
所以在某种程度上
So for degrees.
哲人说生即是死
Life is death say the philosopher's.
我不是很明白
But I'm afraid I don't follow that,
你是说你不信仰上帝
you saying you don't believe in God.
印加人当然是信仰太阳神的
The Incas of course were sun worshippers
这个你们都很清楚
as you seem to know well.
这是基于气象的原因
The reason was meteorological
夜里没有太阳 作为山地的居民
without sun at night being mountain dwellers
他们会冷得发抖
they shiver, they freeze.
住在海边的人呢?
What about those on the coast?
太阳是永恒不变的
The sun was constant.
是天上的暴君
A tyrant in the sky.
所以他们崇拜的是相对小一些的神明
And so it was the lesser god they worshiped,
月亮
the moon.
月宫
the house of the moon
小孩被拿去祭月
The young children were sacrificed.
躺在五颜六色的羽绒和棉花床上
Lying on beds of colored wool and cotton.
为什么呢?
Why?
为什么要把小孩当作祭品?
Why must the children be sacrificed?
呃 不只是小孩 Jack
Well not just the children Jack.
当部落酋长死去的时候
When the chieftain died
习俗就是让他最心爱的 最漂亮的女人一起陪葬
it was customary to bury him with the most beautiful and best loved women.
天哪 他的妻子吗?
Good God his wife?
他的妻子
His wife.
还有他最心爱的妾氏
His favorite concubines.
或多或少
And a considerable number more or less
还有数量可观的仆人 珠宝 天然的银子
of his servants, His jewels, raw silver,
僧侣 武器 食物和衣服
Iamas, weapons, food and clothing.
所以在他的哲学里 死即是生
So in his philosophy death was life.
当然了 为什么不是呢?
But of course why not?
那种气氛持续了好几个小时
It continued in that vein for hours.
各种各样的玄虚的理论
All kinds of mysticism.
大都是我无法理解的
Mostly beyond my comprehension.
Malobar的寡妇们
The widows of Malobar.
在她们的丈夫遗体火化的烈焰中
Burnt themselves in the blaze
自焚了
of the remains of their husbands
以示忠诚
as a demonstration of fidelity.
我无法描述的是
What I can't describe
他的话对在场的人的影响
is the effect it had on the company,
特别是女士们
the ladies in particular.
就好像他给她们施了催眠术一样
It was if he had them mesmerized.
还有在他离开之后 Carlotta...
And yet after he left, Carlotta...
他真是令人厌恶
He was repulsive.
你觉得他...
You found him?
令人厌恶
Repulsive.
你不想我们再见到他吗?
You'd rather we didn't see him again?
他是你的朋友
He's your friend.
过来
Come to me.
第二天早上之后
The following morning
我就从此成了
hence subsequently
她发泄痛苦的对象
I became the object of her pain.
但是Stockton和你的孩子的死
But the connection with Stockton
之间的联系呢?
and your baby's death.
我是说 如你所述
I mean as you describe the evening
两者之间很难形成什么联系啊
it's hard to forge a link.
我知道 可是从那晚上起
I know but it all went wrong Watson
一切就都不对劲了 华生
from that evening.
屋子里就像笼罩着一团乌云...
This house was if there was a black cloud...
我无法描述 我真希望我能说得清楚
I can't describe it I wish to God I could.
有那么多的巧合
There's so many coincidence.
啊 Jack
Ah Jack.
这是我的儿子 Jack
My son, Jack.
过来见见我的朋友们
Come and meet my friends,
华生医生和福尔摩斯先生
Dr. Watson and Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
我打扰你们了
I'm interrupting.
Jack 你丝毫没有打扰我们
Jack you're not interrupting at all
过来坐下跟我们谈谈
now come and sit down and talk to us.
音乐怎么样了 Jack?
How's the music Jack?
你还在练习小提琴吗?
You still practicing the violin?
Jack得到了一把新的小提琴
Jack's been given a new violin,
是他继母给他的礼物
a gift from his stepmother.
旧的那把音色不错啊
The old one plays rather well, usually.
福尔摩斯也会拉小提琴
Holmes plays the violin.
等你继母完全康复了 Jack
I look forward to meeting your stepmother Jack
我很想见见她
when she's sufficiently recovered.
当然了
Indeed.
我们看看现在合不合适吧
Well let us see if now is not the moment.
Mason太太 麻烦你到楼上去一下好吗?
Mrs. Mason would you go upstairs?
噢 她不在房间里 先生
Oh she's not in her room sir.
她很早就出去了
She went out early.
不在吗?
Not.
你怎么没告诉我?
Well why didn't you tell me this?
呃 我以为你知道呢
Well I thought you knew?
她们两个都出去了 父亲
They both went out father.
单独出去吗?
Alone?
Stockton先生来接她们
Mr. Stockton came for them.
他是来关心她们的 先生
He came to pay his respects sir.
就是你在外头骑马的时候 父亲
When you were out riding father.
你看见她们跟他一起走了吗?
And you saw them leave with him?
我的妻子和女仆? 自愿的吗?
My wife and the maid willingly?
你们俩都看见了吗?
You both witnessed this?
噢 他们说就去兜一下风
Oh just for a short drive they said.
到户外去 让她们的脸色红润起来
To take the air, put color in their cheeks.
真的该让我知道
I really should have been informed of this.
我的妻子还不太舒服
My wife is not herself.
是Stockton先生
Was it Mr. Stockton
说服她去兜什么愚蠢的风吗?
who persuaded her on this foolish drive?
是谁鼓动的?
Who instigated it?
你怎么这么担心呢 父亲?
Why does it worry you father?
三个都没事 Ferguson先生 他们回来了
All's well Mr. Ferguson, they're coming home.
Stockton?
我不知道你要来
I didn't realize you had come by.
你本该告诉我的
I wish you would have told me.
女士们怎么样了?
How are the ladies?
很好
Very well.
我们在乡间兜了一圈 很愉快
We had a pleasant drive through the countryside.
空气清新
The air is fresh.
走了
Move on.
他真够有胆量的
Nerve of him.
那么你并无偏见了?
You keep an open mind then?
全然违背逻辑 我想是的
Against all logic I suppose yes.
那歇洛克 福尔摩斯呢?
And Sherlock Holmes?
在英国的犯罪领域中
Such things do not happen
还不曾发生过这样的事情
in criminal practice in England.
有僵尸走过这片土地
The notion of the undead walking this earth
拿无辜的妇女们饱餐一顿
feasting off innocent females
这种想法违背了他的理性认知
offends against all his reasoning.
作为一名神职人员
What is your own view Reverend
您的看法是什么 牧师?
as a man of the church?
生与死都是神秘的 医生
Life and death are mysterious states doctor.
我们对两者的力量都知之甚少
We know little of the resources of either.
Carlotta 亲爱的 开门
Carlotta my darling open the door.
Carlotta 请你开门
Carlotta open the door please.
Carlotta 开门!
Carlotta open the door.
Jack?
福尔摩斯 本地的医生病倒了
Holmes the local doctor has taken his bed.
这儿似乎需要我的服务了
It seems my services are called for.
我希望不是传染病
I hope its not catching.
不是的 我从来不会得传染病
No I never catch anything.
你在忙什么?
What are you up to?
我的第一次出诊是去看旅馆老板的女儿
My first call's the daughter at the inn.
她病得不轻
She's not at all well.
葬礼之后
He took the crippled boy
他把那瘸腿的男孩带到他的房子里头去
into his house after the funeral.
整个下午都在他房子里
All afternoon in his house.
那男孩子六点钟才回去
the boy didn't come back till six o'clock.
她不会死吧 医生?
She's not going to die is she doctor?
不会的 但会经历一个危险期
No but she will pass through a crisis.
她需要最悉心的照料
And needs the greatest care.
现在该让她睡觉
She should sleep now.
这个村子瘟疫流行了吗?
This village is plagued.
就像其他许多村庄一样
Like many another at this time of the year
一年中这个时候总会有流感
with influenza.
你这肮脏丑陋的混蛋
You dirty filthy bitch.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing
你以为我不知道...
You think I couldn't see you?
你和Vera就要完了吗?
With Vera lying at deaths door?
Vera?
别假装你不知道
Don't pretend you didn't know.
她才是你的女人 Michael
She's your girl Michael
不是那个外国来的渣滓
not that foreign trash.
不 妈妈
No Mom.
妈妈 别哭了
Mom don't cry.
自从他们来到这里
Ever since they come here
就只有麻烦
there's nothing but trouble
谁知道那个人带来了什么
and what with him know that man.
哪个人? Stockton先生吗?
What man, Mr. Stockton?
他会把所有人都杀死的
He's killing everyone.
Michael
Michael.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
这是一种特权
This is a privilege.
我们出去逛逛吧 这么个温和的夜晚
Let's stroll out I think on such a balmy evening.
在村子里逛吗?
In the village?
我有马车
I have my carriage.
乡间 多么令人愉快啊
The countryside how delightful.
你为什么...
So why are you?
到这儿来?
Here?
为了我的健康
For my health.
在一个被死亡和阴暗笼罩的乡村?
In village riddled with death and gloom?
不过不是被犯罪所笼罩
But no crime.
你会把手放在胸口
You will lay your hand on your heart
发誓你不是来调查我的吗?
and say your not investigating me?
怎么了? 你干了什么?
Why what have you done?
会有几个人告诉你
There are several who will tell you
我被认为做过什么还有我是干什么的
what I'm alleged to have done,and what I am.
坏天使 死神的先驱
Bad angel precursor of death.
流言不是真相
No truth in the rumor.
我只是在过我的日子 福尔摩斯
I'm living my life Holmes.
一个人还能干什么呢?
What more does a man do?
你教小提琴吗?
You teach the violin?
Jack? 是的
Jack? Yes.
-但那不是... -我的主业?
But that is not... My main occupation?
不是的
No.
我研究古代习俗
I study antiquities.
南美印第安人的
Religious cults and customs
宗教祭祀仪式和风俗
among the South American Indians.
在那个领域我是小有名气的
I have a modest reputation in that field.
出版过什么吗?
Published?
两本书
2 books.
你对我的研究领域熟悉吗?
You're familiar with my subjects?
我到东方旅行过
My travels took me East.
西藏吗?
Tibet?
现在则是宁静的英国乡村了
And now the quiet of English countryside.
我在对家族的历史做些小小的溯源
I'm tracing a little family history.
这里是你家族原来的居住地吗?
This is your family home?
Sinclair大人的领地
The seat of Lord Sinclair.
村里人都觉得我的祖先们是吸血鬼
The villages believe my forbearers were vampires.
某一起与村里的少女们有关的事件
Some incident involving one of their maidens.
Janet Barrows
Janet Barrows,
你曾带了一朵玫瑰去了她的墓地
whose grave you were at with a rose.
你很善于观察
Observant of you.
他们烧了这座房子 肆无忌惮的复仇
They burnt this house an act of unbridled revenge.
而现在他们都在愧疚中煎熬
And now they suffer from the guilty fear
唯恐我回来惩罚他们
that I've come back to punish them.
那是否就是你的目的?
Is that your purpose?
毫无意义的担忧
What a pointless exercise.
来吧 我带你到处看看
Come let me show you around.
我跟你一样 是来调查的
I am like yourself, an investigator.
可以跟我说说你的发现吗?
May I share your findings?
不行
No.
我想听听你的看法
I want your opinion.
在你看来 世上是否有吸血鬼存在?
Do vampires exist in your philosophy?
以人的形式存在嘛 也许有的
In human terms perhaps.
那么你现在看到的是不是一只吸血鬼呢?
And are you looking at one now?
这座房子从前肯定散发着糜乐的气息
From this house must have emanated one spoiled from conviviality.
我也许就是回来重拾这种气息的
I may come back to restore it.
乡村生活对我来说甚为无趣
Life in the village holds few delights for me.
你为什么要把Ferguson太太带到这儿来?
Why did you bring Mrs. Ferguson here?
不  不要
No.
Stockton  怎么了?
Stockton what is it?
我...我...我是...
I...I...I'm...
什么?
What?
你够不够朋友?
Are you a friend?
当然
Yes.
我是你的朋友
Your friend.
我不能告诉任何活着的人
I cannot tell a living soul.
我不能
I cannot.
你不能说什么?
What can't you tell?
死亡女神
Mistress Death.
她和我们在一起
She is with us.
她贪得无厌
insatiable.
让她离我远远的!
Keep her away from me!
华生
Watson
我妻子把门栓死了
my wife has bolted her door,
我的儿子Jack又不理我
my boy Jack has banished me.
村民们怎么样了?
How fares the village.
哦 药物会治好他们的病
Oh medicine should cure their ills.
你妻子发烧吗?
Does your wife have a fever?
让我看看她吧
Let me visit.
她所得的病非药物可以治疗
What she has is beyond medicine.
它占据了她的灵魂
It's taken charge of her soul,
深入骨髓
her very bones.
不是悲伤吗?
Is it not grief?
不是的 我知道悲伤是什么样子
No I recognize grief.
我理解悲伤的感觉
I understand grief.
这是某种毒害
This is some other poison
我们都知道它是从哪儿来的
and we know its source you and I.
我该怎么做呢 华生?
What am I to do Watson?
袖手旁观 让他把我们所有人都毁掉吗?
Just stand aside and it him destroy all?
放松些 老朋友
Easy old man.
福尔摩斯怎么看?
What does Holmes make of it?
他觉得我们都疯了吗?
Does he think were all mad?
我见到了一个鬼
I've seen a ghost.
我不相信
That I don't believe.
你见过?
You?
鬼是不会让你感兴趣的
It didn't appear to you.
这个鬼就会
This one did.
表面看上去是的
Appear so.
似乎我太接近了
It seems I got too close.
太接近什么?
Too close to what?
迟些时候再解释
I'll explain later.
那女孩怎么样了?
How's the girl?
哦 她会康复
Oh she'll recover
没有比流感更险恶的了
it's nothing more sinister than influenza.
似乎年轻人之中流感爆发得特别厉害
It seems to have struck the young in particular.
年轻人?
The young?
村里有六个女孩传染上了
Half a dozen young girls of the village.
流感吗?
Influenza?
具有所有常见的病症:
All the usual symptoms:
夜汗 昏睡  毫无生气
night sweats, drowsiness, lethargy.
哦 Ferguson在楼下
Oh Ferguson's downstairs.
我们去会会他
We'll join him.
首先我们必须明白这一点
First we must understand this.
谢谢 Gresty太太
Thank you Mrs. Gresty
-非常提神 -好的 谢谢
most reviving Yes thank you.
吸血鬼即使是在传说中 也并非一定是个死人
The vampire. Even the legend was not necessarily a dead man.
活人也可以做出这样的举动
A living person might attempt such behavior.
你是说Stockton就是其中一个?
Your saying Stockton is one of these creatures?
我们知道
There are people we know
有些人像海绵那样吸食他人的能量
who suck up the energies of others like a sponge.
把他们的活力都吸取出来据为己有
Draw out their resources
使他们虚弱不堪
and pocket them leaving them fatigued.
再也无法控制自己的意志
No longer master of their wills.
这是一种心理现象
It's a psychological phenomenon.
医生们也都公认这一点
Doctors have acknowledged it.
是的 这种人确实存在
Yes they exist.
在某种程度上 你所说的的确符合
What you say does describe in some measure
与那天晚上他来用餐时的景象
that night he came to dinner
还有他对Carlotta与女仆的影响
and the effect he had on Carlotta and the maid.
刚才我自己也感受到了
I had a taste of it myself just now.
你那撞鬼的经历呢?
And your ghostly experience?
目前我不相信我所看到的景象
I don't, for the moment, believe what I saw.
但我的确接受了那种幻觉
But I do accept hallucination.
另一个人强迫我的心智欺骗了我
The mind forced by another to play tricks.
催眠
Hypnosis.
Stockton曾跟南美印第安人
Stockton has spent much time
一起呆过很长的时间
with the South American Indians
研究他们古老的秘密
studying their ancient mysteries.
他很有可能
It's quite possible
在那里学到了什么
that he learned something out there.
受到一次经历的影响
Was effected by an experience.
但你并没有因此就证明他无罪吧?
But you don't exonerate him for that surely?
没有 但他很有可能得了某种病 治疗以后也许会有起色的
No but he could be suffering a form of illness, which may respond to treatment.
那我们就只能让他滥杀无辜了?
And meanwhile we let him run amuck?
那家伙是很有破坏性的
The man is destructive.
福尔摩斯 你不会否认这一点吧?
Holmes you're not denying that.
如果我们任由他破坏...
He's only destructive if we let him be.
如果我们相信太多的神话...
If we believe too many tales
或者或多或少 把他当成我们内心恶意的载体
or use him as nothing more or less
他才会有破坏性
than a depository for our own ills.
你是说我就是这么干的吗?
Are you suggesting that I am doing that?
我想村子里本身就有危机
I think there's a danger of it in this village.
我跟这个村子站在一起 福尔摩斯
I stand with this village Holmes,
我住在这里
I live here
而且我还看到了他对他人造成的直接影响
and I have seen his direct influence over people.
对我们所爱的人
Loved ones.
一个无辜的毫无防备能力的婴儿死了
A defenseless, innocent baby is dead.
如果你还觉得那是正确的 我们就只好分道扬镳了
Now if you can justify that we part company.
晚安 福尔摩斯
Good night Holmes.
对问题做出诊断是一回事 华生
It's one thing to diagnose the problem Watson.
而通常要解决它又是另一回事
It's quite another, often, to resolve it.
是的 小姐
Yeah your ladyship
这是一个绝对灵验的护身符
here is a charm that cannot fail.
把它别在你的枕头上
Pin this to your pillow and you can laugh.
那对着夜里来犯的伪君子和吸血鬼
Laugh in the face of vampires
你就可以当面耻笑他们了
and hypocrites that visit in the night.
只需六便士就可以保证你的安全
Your safety a sixpence.
有个骗子在招摇撞骗
There's a jackal at work.
我要去伦敦了
I'm off to London.
伦敦?
London?
你可以坚守堡垒到黄昏吗?
Till nightfall will you hold the fort?
当然可以
Certainly.
我觉得拜访一下Carlotta Ferguson
I thought a visit to Carlotta Ferguson
也许会有些帮助
might be useful.
作为医生 我也许可以进去看她
As a doctor I might get in to see her.
有意思
Interesting.
同时跟她丈夫重修旧好
Also patch things up with her husband.
没必要让他反对我们
No point in having him against us.
没错
Quite so.
Saint Sebastian会守护你的心灵
Saint Sebastian, he will protect your heart
免受吸血鬼 和常见的邪恶的侵害
from vampires and prevalent malignants
比如盗尸贼 蝙蝠和吸血蝙蝠
such as ghouls, bats and bat suckers.
给九便士就是你的了
Yours for nine pennies only.
给你所爱的人吧 先生
For your loved ones sir.
她病倒了吧?
Taken back, was she?
这个会打倒魔鬼 让他夜里不再光临
This will beat the devil and his night visits.
它是藏在修女们的衣服里
It was smuggled in the habit of a nun
一路从罗马偷运过来的
all the way from Rome
是以教皇的精神
and was forged
来铸造的
in his holiness own spirit.
哦 它是那么美
Oh it's so beautiful.
现在任何恶人都不能近我的身了
Now I am safe from all bad people.
别吵
Silence.
不许那样
Quit that.
Burns
Burns.
戒指环绕着蔷薇 口袋里装满了花束...
Ring around the rosy. Pocket full of posy...
去车站
To the station.
回头见 华生
See you later Watson.
Michael
Michael.
我给你带了这个
I got you this.
可以帮你好起来
Help ye get better.
那是什么Michael?
What's that Michael?
什么?
What?
你刚和她在一起吗?
You've been with her.
没有啊
No.
-Vera -出去
Vera. Get out.
-Vera -滚啊
Vera. Go on get out.
-Vera -放开我!
Vera. Leave me!
-别碰我 -Vera
-Don't touch me. -Vera.
出去!
Out!
华生医生 进来吧
In here Doctor Watson.
她感觉怎么样了?
How is she fairing?
她没告诉我
She doesn't tell me.
华生医生 夫人
Doctor Watson Madame.
谢谢
Thank you.
Ferguson太太?
Mrs. Ferguson?
我现在代履村医之责 他病了
I'm standing in locum for the village doctor who's sick.
是的
Yes.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你昨天来过
You were here yesterday.
请坐吧
Please sit down.
你希望跟我说什么呢?
So what is it you wish to say to me?
想问问经历了这么悲痛的损失后 你还好吧
To ask how you are after your tragic loss?
需不需要什么有助睡眠的药物?
If you need anything for sleeping?
世上没有任何药物
There are no remedies in the world
能让我夜里睡得着觉的 医生
that would make me sleep at night doctor.
是的 我明白
Yes I understand.
但今天不同
But the day's different.
我睡着了
I sleep.
至少不知不觉地几个小时过去了
At least hours fly by without me.
想喝点什么吗?
Do you wish for something to drink?
哦 不 不 不 谢谢
Oh no, no. No thank you.
你的朋友 那位侦探 今天怎么没和你在一起?
You're friend the detective is not with you today.
他去了伦敦
Gone to London.
你丈夫是不是告诉你 歇洛克 福尔摩斯在村子里?
Your husband told you that Sherlock Holmes was in the village?
不是我丈夫 不是
Not my husband no.
哦 那就是Stockton先生了?
Oh then it was Mr. Stockton?
Stockton?
是Stockton  是的
It was Stockton yes.
他昨天好心地把我带了出去
He was kind enough to take me out yesterday
跟我的女仆一起兜了风
for a drive with my maid.
你认识Stockton吗?
Do you know Stockton?
不 我从未见过他
No I haven't met him.
福尔摩斯认识他
Holmes knows him.
他昨天也坐车去了 一所废弃的旧房子
He too went for ride yesterday to an old ruined house.
哦 是的
Oh yes.
那房子
The house.
你去过那里吗 夫人?
You've been there Madame?
只不过是座烧毁了的房子
It's just a burned out house.
我毫无兴趣
No interest to me.
没有鬼吗?
No ghosts?
我想有很多吧
Many I should think
不过没有一个出来溜达的
but none came out to play.
你觉得Stockton怎么样?
What do you make of Stockton?
他似乎能激起人们强烈的情感
He seems to arouse strong feelings in people.
是什么情感呢?
What should that be?
我说不清楚
I couldn't tell you.
我只不过是听说的
It's only what I've heard.
你想听我对Stockton的看法吗?
You want my opinion on Stockton?
呃 起初我不喜欢他
Well at first I disliked him
他对我的国家很感兴趣
then he was interested about my country.
又会讲我们的语言 于是我自然欢迎他
He speaks my language and so I welcome him.
-可是村子里... -我对村子完全不了解
-But the village... -I know nothing of the village.
激烈的情绪  正如你说的
Strong feelings you say.
乡巴佬...英国的乡巴佬
Peasants...English peasants.
而Stockton给了你一些安慰?
And Stockton offered you some consolation?
他了解死去的人
He understands the dead.
了解我们所发生的事情
What happens to us.
了解我们的去向
Where we go.
知道我的小Ricardo去了哪里
Where my little Ricardo has gone.
那是我仅有的安慰
It's the only solace I have.
从你丈夫身上你得不到安慰吗?
You have none with your husband?
一点也没有
None.
他干嘛要把我带到这么个糟糕的地方来?
Why did he bring me here to this terrible place?
我告诉你吧 因为他想让我的小孩子
I tell you because he wanted my little baby
变成一个像Jack那样的英国佬
to be an Englishman like Jack.
他想要另一个Jack
He wanted another boy like Jack.
死后埋在一个英国人的墓地里 就真的那么好吗?
Is that so wonderful to end up buried in an English grave?
要是我让你难过了 我深表抱歉
I'm sorry if I caused you pain.
有什么关系呢?
Why not?
你是位医生
You are a doctor.
了解真相当然更好
It is better to bring the truth out.
确实如此
Indeed.
你会留下来用午餐吗?
And now you will stay for lunch?
谢谢
Thank you.
我留下来用了午餐还有下午茶
I stayed for lunch, tea.
在花园里喝茶
I had tea in the garden.
她是一个出色的女人
She's a remarkable woman.
非常有教养
Most cultured person.
我想就算是你也会觉得有她陪伴很愉快
I think even you would enjoy her company.
女仆呢?
And the maid?
噢 女仆嘛  呃...
Awe now the maid well.
Michael的脖子上还有吻痕
There are still love marks on Michael's neck.
我只是在回忆细节
And I'm only recalling the details
是因为你想听
since you asked for them.
Ferguson有没有在场?
And Ferguson's part all of this?
Ferguson是在下午三四点回来的
Ferguson returned mid afternoon.
Jack呢?
And Jack?
Jack?
Jack没有回来
Jack hadn't returned.
没人惦记他?
He wasn't missed?
谈起他一两次
Referred to once or twice but missed
至于惦记嘛  我说不清
I couldn't tell you.
这里的那个女孩呢?
And the girl here?
从早上起一直那样
Unchanged since this morning.
你的伦敦之旅呢?
Your trip to London?
我觉得去Stockton的房间看看
I thought a visit to Stockton's room
也许更有帮助
might be more useful.
有没有发生什么事情?
Did anything happen?
没有
Nothing.
活人和死人都没有出现
Neither the living nor the dead appeared.
不过尽管如此还是很有益处的
But it was instructive nonetheless.
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
该死的孩子
Curse the boy.
和你的朋友在一起吗?
With your friend?
呆在里头
Stay in.
进去
Get inside.
Stockton 我要跟你谈谈
Stockton I want to talk to you.
进去
Get in.
进去!
Get in!
看看这里
See here.
你干的好事!
Your work.
我的儿子 妻子 女仆
My boy, my wife, my maid
都是你的了!
you'll have it all
我们成了你乡村宿怨的一部分了
and we're a part of your village vendetta.
抱歉 你在说什么啊?
I'm sorry what are you talking about?
你到底想从我们这儿得到什么?
What do you want from us?
是你把你的妻子介绍给我认识的
You introduced me to your wife.
说英语 你这该死的
Speak English damn you.
说英语!
Speak English!
你竟敢侮辱我
How dare you insult.
不 够了
No enough.
现在把她带走 把你的同类带走
Now take her, take your creature
但是看在上帝的份上 留下我的妻子和儿子
but leave my wife and my boy for God's sake.
Jack  留下
Jack stay.
留下 Jack
Stay Jack.
放开他
Leave him.
让他走
Let him go.
Jack
Jack.
别打了 求你们了
Don't fight please.
我诅咒你 Stockton!
Curse you Stockton
转过那个弯
Came around that bend
车速太快了
Traveling too quick.
地很湿
It's wet.
一次意外 福尔摩斯先生
An accident Mr. Holmes.
我的报告会这么写
That'll be my report.
结案了
Subject closed.
正如你说的有点怪异  警官
A bit odd as you say constable.
很好
Very good then.
过了今天你就要走了 是吧?
You'll be leaving over this day then will you?
现在我们的问题解决了
Now are problem's gone.
我没有留下的理由
No reason for me to stay.
我推断医生今早也有好转
And I gather the village doctor is better this morning
所以你也不再需要华生医生帮忙了?
so you won't be needing Dr. Watson's services either?
是的
No.
但是对他的帮助我们很感激
But his help was appreciated.
呃 来吧小伙子们
Well come on lads,
把事情都干完吧
Iet's get over with.
意外吗?
Accident?
哼
Huh.
谋杀?
Murder?
更难解的谜团之一
One of the deeper mysteries.
他们会把他埋在哪儿?
Where will they put him?
墓地里啊 还能是哪儿?
Graveyard where else?
但他不能埋在那里
But he can't go there.
在我们的国家里 我们有时会火化尸体
In my country sometime they burn the body.
这又不是你们的国家
Well this isn't your country.
我们这儿可是文明的
We're civilized here.
那么你们会把他
So do you would throw him out
扔出去喂狼吗?
to be eaten by wolves?
你会把他埋在哪儿 Jack?
Where would you bury him Jack?
我们说的可是你的朋友Stockton
It's your friend Stockton we're talking about.
你饿吗 亲爱的?
You hungry dear?
不
No.
你干嘛那么看着我?
Why'd you look at me like that?
没什么
Nothing.
呃 我得干活去了
Well I've got to work.
他撞上的是我那棵树
The tree that he hit was my tree.
我从上面摔下来的那棵
The one that I fell from.
你去看过那棵树吗?
You been to see it?
那不是你的树 Jack
No your tree Jack.
那棵树不在那条路上
It wasn't down that way.
它就在那儿
It was.
正好是我发生意外的那棵树
The very same tree where I had my accident.
那棵树应该是受过诅咒
Must have a curse on it.
我想看看
I want to see it.
你带我去看好吗 Michael?
Would you take me Michael?
现在不行
Not now.
你害怕了?
Are you afraid?
不 当然不是了
No of course not.
我带你去
I'll take you.
Michael?
如果你偏要去的话 就迟些时候吧
Later if you must.
世人行动实系徒然
For man walketh in a vain shadow
他们的忙乱亦是枉然...
and disquiet himself in vain.
不是基督教的葬礼
No Christian burial.
她在抗议
Voicing her protest.
就像是颗炸弹 腐蚀了他的荣耀
Like it was a bomb fretting away his honor.
于是每个人都归于虚无
Every man therefore is but vanity.
我向您祈祷 我的主啊
Here my prayer O' Lord
请倾听我的呼唤
and with thy ears consider my calling.
对于我的眼泪求您不要静默无声
Hold not thy peace of my tears
因为在你面前我是一羁旅之人
for I am a stranger with thee
像我的先人一般
and a sojourner as all of fathers were.
噢 求你宽容我 使我在去而不返之前
Oh spare me little that I may recover my strength
重获力量...
before I go hence and be no more...
Jack?
去看看他
Go to him.
噢 求你宽容我 让我重获力量
Oh spare me a little that I may recover my strength.
没事的
It's all right.
呃 我觉得是幽闭恐惧症
Well I think it was claustrophobia.
不是什么更糟的情况
Nothing worse.
有些人在教堂里就会这样
Some people get it in churches.
但是他以前每个周日 都在我的唱诗班里唱歌来着
But he used to sing in my choir every Sunday.
呃 他和Stockton关系比较密切
Well he and Stockton have become quite close.
对他来说应该是个很大的打击
It must have been a terrible shock.
有点像是那么回事
Sort of business.
村里人竭力反对
The village up in arms
但我不会反对为他举行基督教的葬礼的
but I couldn't deny the man a Christian burial.
我是说我怎么能反对呢?
I mean how could I?
他做了什么呢?
What has he done?
他有亲戚吗?
Did have any relatives as?
呃 据大家所知 没有
Well no one as far as anyone knows.
这又带来了另一个问题了
That's another problem you see.
他的房子怎么办?
What to do with his cottage?
还有他的财产呢?
His possessions?
我会去查查那些财产
I shall look over the premises.
我们不问问警察吗?
Shouldn't we ask the police?
福尔摩斯知道该找什么
Holmes will know what to look for.
现在又开始干清理房子的活了吗 福尔摩斯?
In the business of house clearing now hey Holmes?
也许有益处
It may be instructive.
那儿有什么味道?
What's that smell in here?
向日花吗?
Heliotrope?
是腐朽的味道
It's the smell of decay.
麻烦你把那灯点着 华生
Will you light that lamp Watson
我们就可以着手工作了
and then we'll set to work.
鬼吗?
A ghost?
你要是想的话 我会爬上去把他摇下来
I'll climb up and shake him down if you like.
要是他在上面的话
If he's up there.
也吓不倒我啊
It doesn't frighten me.
你吓不了我 Stockton
You can't frighten me Stockton.
你已经埋在草下了
You're under the sod.
那才是你该呆的地方
Where you belong.
你现在烦扰不了任何人了
You won't bother nobody now
再也不会了
nor never again.
Dolly?
得了 别玩愚蠢的游戏了
come on now don't play silly games.
Dolly?
这是Stockton写的
Here's one by Stockton.
秘鲁的宗教
Religions in Peru.
鱼神  蟹之神 飞狐之神
Fish god, Crab god, Fox god in Flight.
禁忌 魔法 巫术
Taboos, witchcrafts, sorcery,
还有什么这人没写到的吗?
is there nothing this man hasn't dabbled in?
吸血鬼
Vampires.
这儿有一本关于吸血鬼的书 福尔摩斯
There's a book here on vampires Holmes.
天哪!
My God!
她受到了袭击
She's been attacked.
就在树下
Down by the tree.
就是他
It was him.
会变成吸血鬼的人 通常是术士
Person to turn vampire generally wizards,
自杀者还有那些
suicides and those who come
横死或受到诅咒的人...
to a violent end or being cursed...
今晚有两个极好的实验品
Tonight 2 perfect specimens
让我汲取力量
from whence I draw my strength.
我的两位秘鲁女人让我重焕生机
My 2 Peruvian ladies revived me.
吸血鬼会把他的受害者
Vampire will bring his victim
带到鬼门关前 却不会让他过去
to the foot of death but not beyond.
他会照料他恢复健康
He will nurse it back to health
用之后所显示出来的爱...
with all the after occurrence of love...
然而现在也许我也受到了控制
And yet I might now also possess
当我去到那房子的时候
when I visit the house
难道不是她让我放弃
is she not commanding me to relinquish,
让我把能力传给另一个人...
to hand my mantel on to another...
事实上也许会再次被爱并把她吞噬
Indeed may be loved and devour her again
这样他就可以永远得到滋养
whereby he's forever nourished.
他呼唤我
He called to me.
把你的梦境告诉我
Tell me your dream.
他让我带她到那儿去 我就照做了
She wanted me to take her there so I did.
本来她还站在那儿的
One minute she was standing there
一下子就不见了
then she was gone.
我看不到她
I couldn't see her.
接着她又在树旁出现了
Then she appeared again by the tree
倒在我怀里
and fell into my arms.
脖子上有咬痕和血迹
On her neck were bites and blood.
是你留下的痕迹吗?
Did you make these marks?
不...不 先生 不是我 是Stockton
No...no sir not I it was Stockton.
你看见他了吗?
You saw him?
呃 没有 不过他就在那儿 错不了的
Well no but he was there right enough.
Stockton死了
Stockton is dead.
不 先生 他没死
No sir he is not
要么就是他是个活死人
or if it is it's the living dead
上帝可以作证
as God's my witness.
看看她身上的齿痕吧 你们自己去看
See the mark on her, see for yourself.
吸血鬼并不存在
Vampires don't exist.
Michael 看着我!
Michael look at me!
他们不存在
They don't exist.
那条狗怎么啦?
What's the matter with the dog?
像是有点四肢麻痹
It some form of paralysis.
是不是突然变成这样的?
Did it come on suddenly?
昨天吧
Yesterday.
很值得注意而且具有启发性
Remarkable and suggestive.
你说的是什么意思?
What do you mean?
这狗与什么事情有关吗?
What's the dog got to do with anything?
此刻我无法告诉你
I can't tell you this instant.
可以允许华生检查一下女仆吗?
May Watson be permitted to examine the maid?
当然了
Of course.
那人的死也许有部分是我造成的
The man's death perhaps in part I caused it.
我不否认我发了脾气 福尔摩斯
I don't deny that I lost my temper Holmes.
但相比起这个家庭所遭受的痛苦 那算不上什么
But that's nothing.to the suffering that's been brought to this family,
我妻子 我的孩子
my wife, the baby boy
而现在又接着发生在女仆身上
and it continues to be brought now on the maid.
跟我解释啊 福尔摩斯
Explain that to me Holmes.
早上好 Jack
Good morning Jack.
福尔摩斯先生 你就是那位侦探
Mr. Holmes, the detective.
Dolores好多了 父亲
Dolores is feeling better father.
有点低烧 没别的了
It's a slight fever nothing worse.
她昨晚跟Michael出去了
She was out with Michael last night.
他们遇上了暴风雨
They were caught in a storm.
吻痕吗?
Lover's marks?
不是的
No.
那是什么?
Then what?
那棵树还是...
This is also the tree
Jack小时候摔下来的那棵呢
that Jack fell from as a boy
那次摔下来让他受了伤
that caused his injury
他就是这么告诉Michael的
or so told Michael.
Stockton和Jack?
Stockton and Jack?
太难以接受了
Now that's too much to swallow.
Jack在撒谎
Jack was lying.
我问了Ferguson
I asked Ferguson.
Jack的那棵树在林子的那一头
Jack's tree is in quite another part of the woods.
但是他为什么要撒谎呢?
But why should he lie about that?
为什么?
Why indeed?
我无能为力
Out of my hands
是警官决定的
it was the constable, he decided.
我们不能这样
We can't.
这是违背法律的
It's outside the law.
是一种侵犯
It's a violation.
亡灵们会怎么看呢?
Well what will the spirits make of it?
我们要把他带去哪儿 Gresty先生?
Where we taking him Mr. Gresty?
回到他该去的地方
Back to where he belongs
去他不能再危害村子的地方
where he can do this village no harm.
他想勒死我
He tried to strangle me.
来些水 Gresty太太
Some water please Mrs. Gresty?
像是只很大的黑色的动物 猫或是蜘蛛
It was like a big black animal, a cat or a spider.
手心有毛
It had hair on the inside of its hands.
掐住我的脖子
And they covered my throat.
那不过是个噩梦 Vera
It was just a bad dream Vera.
只是个噩梦
Just a bad dream.
我不喜欢这里 Gresty先生
I don't like it here Mr. Gresty
我们把他扔了 赶紧走吧
Let's drop him and get out fast.
放在这儿
Down here.
我们还干点别的吗?
Are we going to do the other thing?
干什么 Michael?
What's that Michael?
我们怎么对付老鼠的 你知道吧?
You know what you do with the rats.
你是个很有点子的人哪 小子
You've been a mind whip boy.
我们不是 不是的
We haven't no.
我不去那儿  我不去
I'm not going down there I won't.
那是什么?
What's that?
是块耳朵
It's from an ear.
会是谁呢?
Who can it be?
发生了一起亵渎神明的事件 华生
There's been a desecration Watson.
我想 Stockton回到了他先辈们的住地
Stockton has been returned to the home of his forbearers I would imagine.
这是警察或主教该管的事
It's the matter of the police or the bishop
目前不该是我们操心的
no concern of ours for the moment.
女孩子怎么样了?
How's the girl.
睡得很安稳
Oh she's calm sleeping now.
有什么痕迹吗?
Marks?
连一道抓痕都没有
Not a scratch.
窗户呢?
Window?
从里面闩上了
Bolted from the inside.
那就是癔病了
The case of hysteria then.
但是那个Ferguson的女仆 福尔摩斯 我发誓...
But the Ferguson maid Holmes, I swear...
是的 我们是该认真对待
Yes that we must take seriously.
-你来吗? -当然了
-You coming? -Of course.
Jack?
她的嘴上滴着血  他看见了
Shed blood on her mouth he saw it.
她跟那个Stockton
She and that man Stockton,
他们两个都是吸血鬼
both of them vampires.
你的女主人现在在哪儿?
where's your mistress now.
Carlotta太太是个妖怪
Mrs. Carlotta she is a monster.
你说什么?
What do you mean?
她就是魔鬼 先生
She's the devil sir.
女仆呢?
The maid then?
男孩子上哪去了?
Where's the boy?
Jack吗? 噢 我想他在房间里吧
Jack? Oh he's in his room I think.
Ferguson先生 我不知道他在哪儿
Mr. Ferguson I don't know where he is.
是毒药
It was poison.
我想是管箭毒碱 (中毒后会死于呼吸肌麻痹)
Curare I think.
她不会死吧?
Will she live?
不会
Yes.
Carlotta发现了 她想把毒液吸出来 他知道的
Carlotta discovered it was attempting to suck the venom out, he knew.
从Stockton那偷来的
Started from Stockton or perhaps
或者是Stockton给了他
Stockton gave it to him.
浸过管箭毒碱的箭
An arrow dipped in curare.
造成脖子处两个小小的伤口
2 small incisions into the neck.
他先是在狗身上做实验
He tried it on the dog first.
Jack?
我知道在房间里的可能是Jack
I knew it couldn't be Jack in the room.
我听见他在Stockton的屋子里拉琴
I heard him playing the violin at Stockton's house.
那个鬼怪又是怎么回事?
And what about the ghost?
利用光线搞的把戏
Trick of the light.
但是废墟成了Jack的游戏场所
But the ruin had become Jack's playground.
我第二次去那里就看到他了 现在在这里又看到了
I saw him there on my second visit and now here.
他的灵感都藏在橱柜里
His inspiration hidden away in cupboards
一个心理失常的少年心中 被幻想出的黑暗世界
a dark world of imagination brought alive by a disturbed adolescent boy.
但是假装成吸血鬼...
But to pretend to be a vampire.
不 华生 是相信
No Watson believe.
他相信他自己是个吸血鬼
Believe he is a vampire.
还记得他在教堂里的举止吗?
Remember his behavior in the church?
他对十字架的恐惧?
His fear of the cross?
Stockton也是吗?
And Stockton too?
是的
Why not?
他注意到Stockton对人们造成的影响
He saw Stockton's affect upon people.
他对女人的控制力
His control over women.
为了赢得尊敬 友爱 也许还有爱情 还有什么比当这个更好呢?
What better thing to be? To win the respects, affection, love perhaps,
我们必须找到他
we must find him.
他会在废墟里跟他的主人在一起
He'll be at the ruin with his master.
愿你坠入地狱 炼狱之火燃烧不歇
Get thee to hell burn forever and a day.
愿你邪恶的身躯被豺狼吞噬
Let thy foul carcass be food for jackals.
愿你的阴谋无法得逞
Let thy plot be trickful.
头部受到了重击
its a Blow to the head.
确保他能活下去 华生
See that he lives Watson.
Jack?
她们要回到她的国家去
Well they are returning to her country.
这个村子没有什么可以让她们留恋了
They have nothing in this village to keep them
也没有可以挽留你们的了 我的好朋友们
and neither have you my good friends
不过我永远会心怀感激 将你们付出的努力铭刻在心
but I for one shall remember your efforts with gratitude.
Stockton的事呢?
This business with Stockton?
我会悄悄调往另一个教区 不再操心
I'll remove to another parish quietly, no fuss.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
再见
Goodbye.
那婴儿呢 福尔摩斯? 你该不会认为...
The baby Holmes? You don't think...
我尊重你的专业意见
I respect the verdict of your profession.
肺炎 不是吗?
phenomena wasn't it?
那Stockton的死呢?
And Stockton's death?
意外或是命运 谁知道呢 不过Jack不是谋杀犯
Accident, fate, who knows but Jack was no murderer.
挂坠里Stockton的肖像又是怎么回事?
Stockton's face in the locket?
一个聪明的孩子从一张照片中得到的
Got from a photograph by a clever child.
这些事件会被记录下来吗
Will there be any record of these events?
Lamberley的吸血鬼
The vampire of Lamberley.
不
No.
也许世人对此还没有做好心理准备
Perhaps the world is not yet prepared.